A Guide to the Secretary of Transportation Records, 1998-2001
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Secretary of Transportation Records, 1998-2001
Library of Virginia
38991
14 cu. ft.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Privacy protected information closed for 100 years after date record created. Types of records restricted include, but are not limited to: Commonwealth of Virginia employment applications, job interview notes, employee performance reviews, and employee grievance materials that were sent to the Secretary of Transportation and are part of the constituent correspondence series. Privacy protected material has been sealed but has not been removed from the collection.
Acquisition Information
Transferred from Cathy M. Ghidotti, Office of the Secretary of Transportation, 10 January 2002.
Biographical/Historical Information
In 1970, the Governor's Management Commission Study recommended the creation of six "Deputy Governors" to assist the Chief Executive in his managerial duties. Compatible functions of government were grouped under these administrative heads, who would serve as the Governors top management team or "secretariats," as they were called now. Governor Linwood Holton's top priority for the 1972 session of the General Assembly was a proposal for a Governor's Cabinet, reorganizing the state agencies into six major departments--each headed by a secretary appointed by the governor. Transportation and public safety was one of these six departments.
The office of Secretary of Transportation and Public Safety was created on 8 April 1972, by an act passed by the General Assembly. Governor Holton appointed Wayne A. Whitham, a member of the Winchester City Council, as the first Secretary of Transportation and Public Safety. When Whitman took office on 1 July 1972, he was responsible for the State Highway Commission, Division of Motor Vehicles, Department of State Police, Highway Safety Division, Office of Emergency Services, Department of Military Affairs, Virginia State Crime Commission and the Law Enforcement Officers Training Standards Commission.
The Office has undergone a series of administrative reorganizations since 1972. On 12 April 1976, the Legislature established separate secretariats for transportaion and for public safety, effective 1 July 1976. On 1 July 1984, the offices were again combined. Most recently, the Secretary of Transportation and Public Safety were divided into separate secretariats on 22 February 1990. The Secretary of Transportation is a member of the Governor's Cabinet, and is appointed by the governor, subject to confirmation by the General Assembly.
Currently the Secretary of Transportation is responsible for the direction or juridisction over the following state agencies and boards: Department of Transportation, Department of Rail and Public Transportation, Department of Aviation, Department of Motor Vehicles, Virginia Port Authority, and the Motor Vehicle Dealers Board. Governor-elect James Gilmore appointed Shirley Ybarra, deputy Secretary of Transportation in the Allen administration, secretary. Ybarra previously worked as a special assistant to Transportation Secretary Elizabeth Dole during President Ronald Reagan's administration. Ybarra served until the end of Gilmore's administration in January 2002.
Scope and Content Information
The records of the Secretary of Transportation consist of constituent correspondence to the Governor referred to the secretary for response and correspondence and subject files arranged by department. Constituent correspondence are arranged by tracking numbers assigned by the Governor's office and date recieved. Subjects included are transportation issues, road projects such as I-81, I-72, Route 29, the Springfield interchange and the Woodrow Wilson Bridge, the car tax, and complaints about the Virginia Department of Transportation and the Virginia Department of Motor Vehicles. Shirley J. Ybarra, Secretary of Transportation, Arthur N. Bowen III, Deputy Secretary of Transportation, James F. Hayes, Deputy Secretary of Transportaion, and Charles D. Nottingham, Assistant Secretary of Transportation, wrote responses to these letters. Additional correspondence are arranged by department, then by subject.
Notable topics include the National Air and Space Museum Annex, the Aviation World's Fair 2003, Personal Property Tax Relief Act of 1998 (car tax), Woodrow Wilson Bridge, Springfield Interchange, and copies of Secretary Ybarra's speeches. Notable documents concerning the car tax include: a decision brief for Governor Gilmore (dated 18 May 1999), prepared by Scott D. Pattison, Director of the Department of Planning and Budget, recommending a transfer of second year appropriations be made prior to 1 July 1999 for personal property tax relief; Policy Decisions and Guidance from the Attorney General regarding Personal Property Tax Relief Act implementation (ca. 1998); Summary of meetings between Secretary of Transportation/Department of Motor Vehicles staff and the Governor's Office held between May 1998 and May 1999 concerning implementation of the Personal Property Tax Relief Act; and meeting summaries between the staff of the Department of Motor Vehicles and several Commissioners of the Revenue and Treasurers (23 February 1998 and 2 March 1998) concerning the development of guidelines needed to implement the Personal Property Tax Relief Act.
Contents List
- Constituent Correspondence-1998
  - Correspondence Numbers 153-979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers 985-2770 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2774-5037 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers 8678-16391 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers 16434-17360 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers 17369-20883 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers 20916-22399 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers 22416-24924 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers 25057-25822 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers 25825-26942 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers 26944-27168 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers 27169-27883 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers 28080-28761 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers 28775-29173 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers 29282-29563 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers 29569-29975 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Constituent Correspondence-1998-1999
  - Correspondence Numbers 30037-30592 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers 30624-31013 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers 31035-31333 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers 31385-31793 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers 31808-32214 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers 32222-32780 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers 32784-33211 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers 33219-33890 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers 34001-34890 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers 34892-35712 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers 35717-36044 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers 36099-36761 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers 36762-37536 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers 37566-37993 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers 37999-38478 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers 38482-48988 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Numbers 48993-49262 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Numbers 49318-49935 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Constituent Correspondence-1999
  - Correspondence Numbers 50017-50489 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers 50589-51550 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers 51561-51993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers (no number box)-Mountain Road, Route 33 Petition
  - Correspondence Numbers 51997-52672 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers 52690-53399 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers 53416-54859 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers 54889-55797 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers 55833-56373 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers 56380-57421 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers 57423-58272 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers 58278-59468 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers 59469-61422 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers 61459-62503 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers 62545-64013 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers 64007-64976 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Constituent Correspondence-1999
  - Correspondence Numbers 65003-66795 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers 66817-67582 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers 67673-68382 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers 68406-68732 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers 68739-69654 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers 69704-70167 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Number 70194 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers 70254-71336 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers 71351-72067 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers 72114-72799 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers 73005-74514 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers 74683-75141 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers 75380-76589 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers 76797-77347 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers 77368-77997 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers 78006-78513 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Numbers 78516-79219 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Numbers 79257-79996 (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Constituent Correspondence-1999
  - Correspondence Numbers 80001-80303 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers 80311-81139 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers 81165-81800 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers 81825-82228 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers 82233-82599 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers 82603-82793 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers 82800-83088 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers 83133-83601 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers 83603-84617 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers 84634-85550 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers 85555-86805 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers 86807-87749 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers 87784-89468 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers 89479-89957 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Constituent Correspondence-1999-2000
  - Correspondence Numbers 90225-91781 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers 91790-92439 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers 92440-93642 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers 93645-94795 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers 94800-95244 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers 95280-95398 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers 95399-95842 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers 94843-96691 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers 96693-97380 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers 97385-97912 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers 98110-99324 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers 99327-100835 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers 100857-101501 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers 101531-101981 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Number 101992 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers 102011-102633 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Numbers 102638-103649 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Numbers 103650-103998 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Constituent Correspondence-2000
  - Correspondence Numbers 104002-104494 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers 104535-105951 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers 106018-106653 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers 106688-107999 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers 108014-109812 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers 109824-111109 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers 111270-111981 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers 112188-113860 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers 113963-116193 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers 102751-200347 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers 200352-201006 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers 201027-202912 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers 202933-203402 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers 203406-204486 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers 204505-205363 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers 205366-205852 (Box 7, Folder 16)
- Constituent Correspondence-2000
  - Correspondence Numbers 2032314-2030176 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2031394-2029549 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2029482-2028316 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2028270-2027620 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2027617-2026820 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2026816-2026052 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2026030-2019677 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2018721-2016502 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2016458-2014294 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2014291-2013796 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2013795-2012106 (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2012091-2011289 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2011286-2010934 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2010545-2010169 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2010162-2009403 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2009394-2008662 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2008651-2007735 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2007725-2006593 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2006576-2004904 (Box 8, Folder 19)
- Constituent Correspondence-2000-2001
  - Correspondence Numbers 2071997-2071316 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2071291-2070548 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2070507-2068910 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2068906-2067016 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2066957-2065222 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2065157-2061832 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2063741-2061533 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2061386-2058050 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2058013-2055613 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2055466-2051105 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Number 2051085 (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2050628-2045365 (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2045349-2042862 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2042845-2040603 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2040585-2039518 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2039491-2038336 (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2038248-2036003 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2035951-2035089 (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2034927-2033959 (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2033952-2033069 (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Constituent Correspondence-2001 (some 1998 & 1999 interfiled)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2076601-2076523 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2076522-2075943 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2075938-2075962 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2074997-2074049 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2074048-2073675 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2073674-2073516 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2073493-2073322 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2073321-2073237 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2073236-2073156 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2073156-2073026 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2073025-2072942 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2072941-2072900 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2072896-2072760 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2072760-2078664 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2072663-2072511 (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2072511-2072462 (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2072457-2072203 (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2072202-2072010 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Constituent Correspondence-2001 (some 1998 & 1999 interfiled)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2088620-2087067 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2087065-2085975 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2085974-2084554 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2084490-2083579 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2083608-2082433 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2082367-2081595 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2081549-2080483 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2080481-2079516 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2079489-2079582 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2078978-2078485 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2078433-2077744 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2077681-2077092 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2077095-2075492 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2075416-2076928 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2076787-2076642 (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence Numbers 2076441-2076605 (Box 11, Folder 16)
- Department of Aviation
  - National Air and Space Museum Annex (1 of 4) (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - National Air and Space Museum Annex (2 of 4) (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - National Air and Space Museum Annex (3 of 4) (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - National Air and Space Museum Annex (4 of 4) (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Eastern Virginia Airport System Study (1 of 2) (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Eastern Virginia Airport System Study (2 of 2) (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Airport Revolving Loan Fund (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Richmond International Airport (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Aviation World's Fair 2003 (1 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Aviation World's Fair 2003 (2 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Aviation World's Fair 2003 (3 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 11)
- Department of Motor Vehicles
  - Fees (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - LaRouche (National Democratic Policy Committee/La Rouche v. Commonwealth of Virginia Department of Motor Vehicles) (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Mothers Against Drunk Driving (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Motor Votor-JLARC Study (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - National Low Emission Vehicles (NLEV) (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Personal Property Tax Relief Act (Car Tax) (1 of 4) (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Personal Property Tax Relief Act (Car Tax) (2 of 4) (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Personal Property Tax Relief Act (Car Tax) (3 of 4) (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - Personal Property Tax Relief Act (Car Tax) (4 of 4) (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Point of Taxation for Motor Fuels (1 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Point of Taxation for Motor Fuels (2 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - Point of Taxation for Motor Fuels (3 of 3) (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - United Parcel Service (UPS) (Box 12, Folder 24)
- Department of Rail and Public Transportation
  - Bristol Rail (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Capital Beltway Corridor Rail Reasibility Study (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Conrail Merger (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Dulles Corridor Transit (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Eastern Shore Railroad (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - High Speed Rail (1 of 3) (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - High Speed Rail (2 of 3) (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - High Speed Rail (3 of 3) (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Job Access & Reverse Commute (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Mag Lev Demonstration Project (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Main Street Station (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Short-Line Railraods (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Transit (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Washington/Richmond Rapid Rail (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Virginia Railway Express (Box 13, Folder 15)
- Virginia Port Authority
  - 50-Foot Anchorage Study (1 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - 50-Foot Anchorage Study (2 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Craney Island (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Drayage (CSX) (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Impact of State-Owned Ports on Local Government (Host Cities) (1 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Impact of State-Owned Ports on Local Government (Host Cities) (2 of 2) (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - JLARC Report, "Review of Impact of State Owned Ports on Local Governments" (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - OpSail 2000 (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Shentel ITS (Box 13, Folder 24)
- Department of Transportation
  - HOV in Hampton Roads (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Dulles Greenway Refinancing (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - MPO Boundaries (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - 8-Hour Ozone Non-Attainment Designations (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Six-Year Plan (Virginia Transportation Development Plan) (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Safety Service Patrol (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Virginia Maintenance Services (VMS) (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Woodrow Wilson Bridge (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Capital Beltway Study (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Southeastern Parkway (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Springfield Interchange (1 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Springfield Interchange (2 of 2) (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Utility Accomodation Policy (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - 511 Service (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Competency Based Pay Pilot (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Quinquennial Review (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Smart Road (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Tri-Country Parkway (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Route 50 Traffic Calming (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - I-73 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Route 168 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Route 288 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - I-895 (Pocahontas Parkway) (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Western Transportation Corridor (Box 14, Folder 24)
- General
  - Governor's Commission on Transportation Policy (1 of 3) (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Governor's Commission on Transportation Policy (2 of 3) (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Governor's Commission on Transportation Policy (3 of 3) (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Demonstration Projects (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - GARVEE Legislation (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Innovative Progress Priority Transportation Initiative (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - National Governor's Association (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Y2K (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - Speeches-Shirley J. Ybarra, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Speeches-Shirley J. Ybarra, 2000 (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Speeches-Shirley J. Ybarra, 1999 (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Speeches-Shirley J. Ybarra, 1998 (Box 14, Folder 36)